## ZIA U. MUFTI

### 8225 11TH DR W,APT D-5 EVERETT 98204

425-426-6704 Ziamufti50@gmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

A position where my system engineer knowledge, sales experience and interpersonal skills can be utilized, which can be beneficial for both the employer and my personal growth. Highly capable and intuitive car sales representative offering experience in client relationship, sales, customer service and marketing. Ability to retain customer base, expand sales and drive revenue.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

September 2019- Fab 2020	Car Sales Consultant - Hyundai of Kirkland
	I have been working as a Car sale consultant at Hyundai/Genesis of Kirkland
	Key Responsibilities included: Gathering information regarding customer's
	needs in order to provide ideal service. Making suggestions to customers
	involving trade-ins. Price negotiation and completion of sales or purchase
	contracts with customers. Maximizing profits for the dealership by
	structuring and restructuring finance deals. Processing paperwork
	associated with retail automobile sales including credit application. Follow-
	up with customer base through contact that encourages patronage.
SEP 2013 – June 2019	Dress In – Men's Clothing Store – Owner/Manager – Lahore, Pakistan
	Successfully owned and operated a Men's clothing store for about ten years
	before migrating to the United States in August 2019.
Dec 2010 - June 2013	786 Cellular Zone - Owner/Manager – Lahore, Pakistan
	I owned and managed a cell phone sales and repair store in Lahore,
	Pakistan. Major cell phone brands carried in the store were: Nokia,
	Samsung, Motorola and Sony Ericsson.
Jan. 2008 – Nov. 2010	Ashrafi Foods (Pvt.) Ltd. Key Accounts Franchise Manager – Karachi,
	Pakistan
	A wholesale food business where I worked as a Franchise manager. My
	major responsibilities were Strategic planning and deal negotiations to
	open more Franchise stores in Karachi, Pakistan. I was able to open many
	accounts for Ashrafi foods and those new Franchises carried Ashrafi
	products like Ashrafi Flour, Ashrafi Rice etc.
Jan 2007 – Nov. 2007	Desert Gulf Travel and Tours, LLC – Marketing and Operations Coordinator – Dubai, UAE
	Developed and maintained outstanding relationships with clients and
	exceeded their expectations for customer service while securing their travel
	arrangements.
	Carefully listened to and assessed clients' needs in order to create a match
	for their vacation plans.
	Demonstrated consistent ability to close sales and achieve high
	productivity.
Mar 2005 – Dec. 2006	Global marketing Services (Put) Limited, Assistant Branch Manager – Karachi, Pakistan
	Direct marketing for Unilever, Nestle, Shan Food, Inc. products. It involved
	door to door introduction and selling of these brand products.
	My major responsibility was growth of brands territory in the City of

# Karachi. Loyalty referrals and repeat business

## March 2002 – Jan 2004 **Cyber Internet Services (Pvt.) Ltd, Lahore, Pakistan**

Cyber Internet is the largest Internet and Data communication Network services provider in Pakistan. Major Duties Performed were assisting Network operations and providing outside Customer Support for Dialups, dedicated accounts, multilink, ISDN, VPN and some corporate mail solutions. Improved process flows and problem resolution by tracking customer interactions and escalation.

Observed, documented and captured software configurations to resolve an ongoing issue for a key account as the eyes and ears of the Major Account Support Team.

#### **EDUCATION**

2002 – 2003	Diploma in Advanced Network Engineering – Lahore, Pakistan
	Training course in advanced networking technologies from National Engineers training services (Pvt) Limited. The course covered training in Routers, switches, DSL, DXX (Digital Cross Connect), Frame Relay and ATM.
2000 – 2001	Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE 2000) from Soft Logix,
	Institute of Computer language - Lahore Pakistan.
	Microsoft Windows 2000 Accelerated Exam for MCP's
1998 – 1999	Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) - Government College of Science, Allama
	Iqbal Town, Lahore Pakistan.
	Courses taken: Economics, Political Science and English

- Languages Spoken: English, Urdu and Punjabi
- Ability to work under pressure
- Exceptional time management skills
- Capability to adapt new things
- Outstanding listening and negotiation abilities
- Extremely resourceful and diplomatic
- Superb mathematical skills
- Strong team player